Guide to the Lavoisier Manuscripts and Graphics Collection, circa 1750-1834 (bulk)
Lavoisier Manuscripts and Graphics Collection, circa 1750-1834 (bulk)
- Series VI. Certificates, deeds and contracts
  - Title deeds of "Biens nationaux", 1598-1834
    - Deeds made before 1789, 1598-1781
      - Copies of surveyings of the lands located in Taillefontaine purchased by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, ca. 1820-1830
        - [Surveying of the lands belonging to the cure of Taillefontaine ], June 1771 (Box 44, Folder 14)
          Summary: Total: 81 essins 38 verges 1/3.
    - Deeds made during the French Revolution, 1791-1801
      - Documents about the purchase of the farm of La Place by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1791-1792
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, January 16, 1792 (Box 45, Folder 1)
          Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf
        - [Extract of auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, June 8, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 2)
          Summary: Extract of the auction of the lands formerly belonging to the Ursuline nuns of Crépy-en-Valois, purchased by Parisis on behalf of Lavoisier. Total: 517 essins, 80100 pounds.
      - Documents about the purchase of the farm of Soulemont by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1792-1793
        - [Surveying of the farm of Soulemont. (Taillefontaine and Retheuil)], Villers-Cotterêts, 1793 *---* [Extract], Villers-Cotterêts, 15 pluviôse an IV [4 February 1796] (Box 45, Folder 3)
          Physical Description: 24 p.
          Summary: Extract of the surveying made in 1792-1793, of the Farm of Soulemont, purchased by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier in 1791. Total: 181 arpents 50 verges 8 dixièmes.
      - Documents about the purchase of the lands formerly belonging to the canons of Pierrefonds by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1791-1795
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 27 friMayre an IV, December 18, 1795 (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, October 10, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 4)
          Physical Description: 8 p.
          Summary: Extract of the auction of the lands formerly belonging to the canons of Pierrefonds, purchased by Parisis on behalf of Lavoisier. Total: 18,5 esseins, 6025 pounds.
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, October 10, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Documents about the purchase of the lands formerly belonging to the church of Taillefontaine by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1791-1795
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, April 3, 1792 (Box 45, Folder 5)
          Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf.
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 27 friMayre an IV [18 December 1795] *---* [Extract], Soissons, 3 bruMayre an VIII [25 October 1799] (Box 45, Folder 5)
          Physical Description: 2 p. on 1 leaf
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 27 friMayre an IV, December 18, 1795 (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, June 18, 1793 (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, December 10, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 5)
          Physical Description: 7 p.
          Summary: Extract of the auction of the lands formerly belonging to the cure of Taillefontaine, purchased by Parisis on behalf of Lavoisier. Total: 74,5 esseins, 16100 pounds
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, December 10, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Documents about the purchase of the lands formerly belonging to the fabric of the parish of Taillefontaine by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1791-1796
        - [Surveying of the lands formerly belonging to the fabric of the parish of Taillefontaine], Villers-Cotterêts, 1793 *---* [Extract], Villers-Cotterêts, 1er germinal an XIII [22 March 1805] (Box 45, Folder 6)
          Physical Description: 16 p.
          Summary: Extract of the surveying made in 1792-1793 of the lands formerly belonging to the fabric of Taillefontaine, purchased by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier in 1791. Total: 48 arpents 50 verges 8 dixièmes.
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 17 prairial an IV [5 June 1796] *---* [Extract], Soissons, 3 bruMayre an VIII [25 October 1799] (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 17 prairial an IV [5 June 1796] *---* [Extract], Soissons, 19 nivôse an VIII [9 January 1800] (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 17 prairial an IV, June 5, 1796 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 15 floréal an IV [4 May 1796] *---* [Extract] Soissons, 19 nivôse an VIII [9 January 1800] (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (Aisne) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 15 floréal an IV, May 4, 1796 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Soissons, 27 friMayre an IV, December 18, 1795 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Receipt from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, June 18, 1793 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary:
        - [Letter from Michel, mayor of Taillefontaine to Nicolas Charles Parisis], Taillefontaine, to Nicolas Charles Parisis, Villers-Cotterêts, April 1793 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary: Goes with the withdrawal of the opposition made by Michel, churchwarden, on the payment of the rental of the lands formerly belonging to the church of Taillefontaine.
        - [Deed], Taillefontaine, April 1793 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary: Withdrawal of the opposition made by Michel, churchwarden, on the payment of the rental of the lands formerly belonging to the church of Taillefontaine.
        - [Deed], Villers-Cotterêts, August 10, 1792 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary: Opposition made by Michel, churchwarden, on the payment of the rental of the lands formerly belonging to the church of Taillefontaine.
        - [Deed], Villers-Cotterêts, 10 August 1792 *---* Copy (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Document from the Bureau de paix et conciliation (Soissons)], Villers-Cotterêts, March 30, 1793 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary: Summoning to appear of the municipality of Taillefontaine, on Lavoisier's demand, to withdraw the opposition on the rental of the lands formerly belonging to the church of Taillefontaine.
        - [Document from the Bureau de paix et conciliation (Soissons)], Villers-Cotterêts, 30 March 1793 *---* Copy (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, December 28, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          Summary: Extract of the auction of the lands formerly belonging to the fabric of Taillefontaine, purchased by Parisis on behalf of Lavoisier. Total: 84 esseins, 15000 pounds.
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, 28 December 1791 *---* Copy (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Documents about the purchase of the lands formerly belonging to the monks of Bourg-Fontaine by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier, 1791-1792
        - [Surveying of the lands formerly belonging to the monks of Bourg-Fontaine], Villers-Cotterêts, 1792 *---* [Extract], Villers-Cotterêts, 15 germinal an XIII [5 April 1805] (Box 45, Folder 8)
          Physical Description: 12 p.
          Summary: Extract of the surveying made in 1792 of the lands formerly belonging to the Carthusian monks of Bourg-Fontaine, purchased by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier in 1791. Total: 47 arpents 47 verges 6 dixièmes.
        - [Receipt from the Caisse de l'Extraordinaire to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Paris, January 2, 1792 (Box 45, Folder 9)
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, October 18, 1791 (Box 45, Folder 9)
          Summary: Extract of the auction of the lands formerly belonging to the monks of Bourg-Fontaine, purchased by Parisis on behalf of Lavoisier. Total: 75 esseins, 15300 pounds.
        - [Extract of the auction from the DoMaynes nationaux (district de Soissons) to Antoine Laurent Lavoisier], Soissons, 18 October 1791 *---* Copy (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Documents about the purchase of lands formerly belonging to the monks of Valsery by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier
        - [Surveying of the lands located in Vivières formerly belonging to the monks of Valsery ], Villers-Cotterêts, September 1791 (Box 45, Folder 10)
          Physical Description: 12 p. on 3 leaves
          Summary: Surveying of lands formerly belonging to the Premonstratensian monks of Valsery, located in Vivières, purchased by Antoine Laurent Lavoisier in 1791. Total: about 410 arpents
      - Return of the lands purchased by Lavoisier to his widow
        - [Extract of a deliberation of the Justice de Paix of Villers-Cotterêts relating to Madame Lavoisier's properties], Villers-Cotterêts, 27 ventôse an IX, March 18, 1801 (Box 45, Folder 11)
          Physical Description: 20 p.
          Summary: Return of some lands of Taillefontaine and Retheuil to Lavoisier's widow.
        - [Extract of a deliberation of the Justice de Paix of Villers-Cotterêts relating to Madame Lavoisier's properties], Villers-Cotterêts, 27 ventôse an IX, March 18, 1801 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Deeds made after 1801
      - [Lease of the farms of Soulemont and La Place belonging to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Crépy-en-Valois, August 14, 1822 (Box 45, Folder 13)
        Summary: Farming lease between the Comtesse de Rumford, landowner, and Marie Antoine Leclerc and Rosalie Victoire Moulin, his wife, farmers.
      - [Lease of the lands of the fabric of the parish of Taillefontaine belonging to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Crépy-en-Valois, June 12, 1824 (Box 45, Folder 14)
        Summary: Lease between the Comtesse de Rumford, landowner, and Pierre Louis Collard and Marie Catherine Fournier, his wife, farmers.
      - [Lease of the lands of the monks of Bourg-Fontaine belonging to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Crépy-en-Valois, February 10, 1824 (Box 45, Folder 15)
        Physical Description: 10 p.
        Summary: Lease between the Comtesse de Rumford, landowner, and Nicolas Joachim Fournier, and Marie Constance Moulin, his wife, farmers.
      - [Lease of the farms of Soulemont and La Place and other lands located in Taillefontaine belonging to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Crépy-sur-Oise, September 7, 1833 (Box 45, Folder 16)
        Summary: Lease between the Comtesse de Rumford, landowner, and Marie Antoine Leclerc and Rosalie Victoire Moulin, his wife, farmers.
      - [Document about the farm of Soulemont], 1833 (Box 45, Folder 17)
        Summary: "Etat des pièces et titres envoyés à Mr Lefebvre le 20 March 1833 relatifs à Taillefontaine et Soulemont"
      - [Lease of the lands of the monks of Bourg-Fontaine belonging to Marie Anne Lavoisier], Crépy-en-Valois, October 11, 1834 (Box 45, Folder 18)
        Summary: Farming lease between the Comtesse de Rumford, landowner, and Antoine Charlemagne Fournier and Céleste Eléonore Leclerc, his wife, farmers.
- Series VII. Documents relating to institutions to that Lavoisier belonged
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Académie des Sciences
    - Lavoisier, Antoine Laurent, [report on the Académie des Sciences], 1792 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      Summary: "Citoyens/Le payeur de la trésorerie nationale désirant donner aux membres de l'Académie des Sciences les facilités qui dépendent de lui..."
  - Compagnie de la Guyane française
    - Correspondence
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Pierre], Oyapock, [to] Madame [de Beaumanoir], June 6, 1780 (Box 43, Folder 31)
        Physical Description: 9 p. on 3 leaves; letter autographed signed
        Summary: Pierre shows all the difficulties he has to cultivate French Guyana for the Compagnie, his deseases, the deaths of most people who worked for him, his need of more slaves, and his wish to go back to France.
        Letter begins: "Madame/Quand je partis pour la Guyanne, j'étois si flatté de la confiance dont vous aviés parru m'honnorer que je me proposai de vous rendre compte de mes travaux..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Madame de Beaumanoir], [to] Pierre, 1780 (Box 43, Folder 32)
        Physical Description: 3 p. on 1 leaf; letter autographed
        Summary: Regrets that Pierre leaves French Guyana, deplores the difficulties and losses of the Compagnie but wishes he recovers
        Letter begins: "Je suis bien sensible, Monsieur, à l'honneur de votre souvenir et au détail que vous me faittes par votre lettre d'Oyapok en datte du 6 June 1780..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Bajon], Oyapock, [to] Mr de Beaumanoir, Paris, July 1, 1780 (Box 43, Folder 33)
        Physical Description: 2 p. on 1 leaf; letter autograph signed
        Summary: Opposes the project of cultivating French Guyana's lowlands, but is favourable to the cultivation of cotton in highlands.
        Letter begins: "Monsieur/Je n'ai pas oublié les commissions que vous m'avés données lors de mon depart de Paris..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [letter] [to] Monsieur de Beaumanoir, Paris, August 8, 1781 (Box 43, Folder 34)
        Summary: Notice of the general meeting of the Compagnie.
        Letter begins: "Monsieur/MM. Les Directeurs de la Compagnie de la Guyane Françoise ont l'honneur de vous prévenir que l'assemblée de Messieurs les administrateurs..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Claude Julien], Auteuil, [to] Madame la baronne [de Beaumanoir], 23 September 1781 (Box 43, Folder 35)
        Physical Description: 3 p. on 1 leaf; letter autographed signed
        Summary: Asks an appointment with the Baronne de Beaumanoir, to negotiate a lend to the Compagnie.
        Letter begins: "Madame la Baronne/Made la veuve Balthazar ma parente, vient de me faire part de la réponse que vous lui aviés faite hier au soir..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Claude Julien], Auteuil, [to] Madame la Baronne [de Beaumanoir], September 24, 1781 (Box 43, Folder 36)
        Physical Description: 5 p. on 2 leaves; letter autograph signed
        Summary: Foreign bankers accept to lend 2 millions for 10 years to the Compagnie, but ask for the guarantee of the Duc de Penthièvre.
        Letter begins: "Madame la Baronne/Je crois devoir vous faire part des préliminaires qu'exigent mes correspondants de l'étranger pour l'emprunt de 2 millions en question..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [from Claude Julien], Auteuil, [to] Madame la Baronne [de Beaumanoir], September 25, 1781 (Box 43, Folder 37)
        Physical Description: 3 p. on 1 leaf; letter autograph signed
        Summary: Business letter about the Compagnie.
        Letter begins: "Madame la Baronne/A peine mon exprès a-t-il été parti pour Paris, avec ma réponse qu'il vous a portée au billet dont vous m'avés honoré..."
    - Documents and reports
      - [Document], December 14, 1763 (Box 46, Folder 6)
        Summary: Extract of a weekly paper, the Affiches, annonces et avis divers, No. 50, 14th December 1763: an article about a recently published book describing Guyana.
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], April 24, 1779 (Box 46, Folder 7)
        Summary: Decides to borrow 150 000 pounds.
        Letter begins: "Délibération du 24 April 1779"
        Bibliographic Reference:
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française [report], May 10, 1780 (Box 46, Folder 8)
        Physical Description: 7 p. on 2 leaves
        Summary: Losses of the Compagnie, because of the war and ships' capture. Associates decide an increase of capital (1 million pounds), and postpone the payment of interests and dividends.
        Letter begins: "Les intéressés de la Compagnie de la Guyanne française extraordinairement assemblée s'étant fait rendre compte de la situation..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], May 10, 1780 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], 1781 (Box 46, Folder 10)
        Summary: General meeting, liabilities, partial liquidation of the Compagnie.
        Letter begins: "L'Administration de la Compagnie de la Guyanne française désirant prendre un party deffinitif qui puisse rassembler les divers individus qui la composent..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], 1784 (Box 46, Folder 11)
        Physical Description: 9 p. on 3 leaves
        Summary: Liquidation of the Compagnie and payment of liabilities.
        Letter begins: "Nous soussignés/Intéressés dans la Compagnie de la Guyanne Françoise après avoir pris connoissance de la position actuelle des affaires de la Compagnie..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], 1784 (Box 46, Folder 12)
        Summary: About the liquidation of the Compagnie.
        Letter begins: "Pour parvenir à prendre sur les affaires de la Compagnie de la Guyanne une détermination fixe et qui puisse être de l'agrément de tous les intéressés..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [report], s.d. (Box 46, Folder 13)
        Physical Description: 7 p. on 2 leaves.
        Summary: Associates decide a bond (300000 pounds).
        Letter begins: "La Compagnie de la Guyane française assemblée extraordinairement s'étant fait rendre compte de la scituation de ses affaires..."
      - Compagnie de la Guyane française, [document], s.d. (Box 46, Folder 14)
        Physical Description: 3 p. on 1 leaf.
        Document begins: "Etat des actionnaires dont on peut demander la contribution"
  - Régie des poudres et salpêtres
    - France. Régie des poudres et salpêtres, [warrant], Paris, ca. 1775 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf; 47 cm
      Summary: Printed warrant delivered by the Conseil d'Etat to the Sieur Bergaut, allowing him to manufacture and sell saltpeter and powder.
    - France. Régie des poudres et salpêtres, [passport], Paris, ca. 1780 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf; 18 cm
      Summary: Printed blank passport for the transportation of powder and saltpeter.
    - France. Régie des poudres et salpêtres, [warrant], Paris, 1780 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf, 36 cm
      Summary: Printed warrant allowing Pierre Busnel, from Saint-Vaast (Normandy), to provide himself with powder in Caen.
    - France. Régie des poudres et salpêtres, [warrant], Paris, 1786 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: 11 p.; 25 cm
      Summary: Printed warrant nominating Benoît Drieu de la Forte as a Commissaire of the Régie des poudres et salpêtres; description of his activities and duties.
    - Items by or about the Régie des poudres et salpêtres or saltpeter, 1778-1795 (Box 46, Folder 29)
      Physical Description: 6 items; 35 x 23 cm. or smaller.
      Summary: Six items from the collection of Denis Duveeen. (a) Letter concerning saltpeter, addressed to Monsieur le Brigant (sender's name indistinct), May 27, 1778, with poems and notes in another hand on the leaf bearing the address; (b) another letter to M. le Brigant in the same hand, from the same sender and a second one (names indistinct), February 26, 1778; (c) letter from the Comité de salut public to the Régisseurs nationaux des poudres et salpêtres, signed by Carnot and C.A. Prieur, 7e. jour du 2e. mois de la 2e. année de la République; (d) letter from the Ministre des contributions publiques to the Citoyens composant l'Académie des sciences, on the subject "Poudres et salpêtres," signed by Claviere, March 24, 1793, an 2 de la République; (e) "Mémoire" on the subject "Soude artificielle," 1e. brumaire an 3e., unsigned; (f) "Extrait des registres de l'Académie de Dijon du 11 janvier 1781," signed by Mavel [?].
- Series VIII. Documents relating to Lavoisier's relatives or associates
  - Lavoisier, Alexandre
    - [Bond belonging to Alexandre Lavoisier], Paris, March 31, 1792 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf; 23 cm
  - Lavoisier, Jean Antoine
    - [Certificate of the burial of Antoine Laurent Lavoisier's father, Jean Antoine Lavoisier], Le Bourget, 17 September 1775 *---* [Extract], Le Bourget, 2 germinal an XIII (Box 46, Folder 22)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf; 24 cm
  - Lavoisier, Madeleine Philippe
    - [Receipt belonging to Madeleine Philippe Lavoisier], [Paris], 1726 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf of parchment; 13 cm
  - Lavoisier, Marie-Anne-Pierrette
    - [Document about Marie Anne Lavoisier's family], ca. 1935 (Box 46, Folder 28)
      Physical Description: 1 leaf; 65 cm
      Summary: Genealogical chart of the Terray family, to that Marie-Anne Lavoisier belonged.
  - Lavoisier, Marie
    - [Deed relating to Marie Lavoisier], Paris, January 27, 1773 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Lycée des Arts
    - [Poster], 15 thermidor an IV, August 2, 1796 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      Physical Description: 1 p. on 1 leaf; 22 cm
      Summary: About a tribute for Lavoisier organized by the Lycée des Arts, in Paris.
  - Waroquiez, Laurent
    - [Memoir by Laurent Waroquiez], ca. 1720 (Box 46, Folder 19)
      Physical Description: 3 leaves; 24 cm
  - Geneology de la Maison Motier de La Fayette, Undated (Folder 2)
- Series VIIIA. Photocopies of documents held at other repositories
  - Eleutherian Mills Historical Library
    - Poudre et salpêtre--Notes (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: 42 leaves; 36 cm
    - Mémoire sur la poudre (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: approximately 35 leaves; 36 cm. Draft, heavily revised; signed DuPont.
    - Société philomathique, records of expenses, ca. 1793-1799 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: 27 leaves; 28 cm.
    - Mémoire sur le salpêtre (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: 53 leaves; 36 cm.
    - Mémoire sur la construction des moulins a poudre, par Bottée-Toulmont (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: 19 leaves; 36 cm. (first page 29 cm.)
    - Mémoire sur la construction des moulins a poudre, signed Dupont (Box 49, Folder 6)
      Physical Description: 42 leaves; 36 cm. Draft with extensive revisions.
    - Déclaration, par Lavoisier, de ses revenus, 1793 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Physical Description: 5 leaves; 36 cm.
    - Note from Lavoisier to M. Gerodet (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Physical Description: 1 leaf; 28 cm. Addressed to "M. Gerodet, peintre au Louvre."
    - Proces-verbal de la séance du Club de quatrevingt-neuf, September 30, 1790 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Physical Description:[2,] 13 pages on 8 leaves; 28 cm. Printed (Paris: De l'imprimerie de Garnery, [1790?])
    - Letter from La Rochefoucauld-Liancourt to citoyen Harmand, October 18, 1799 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      Physical Description: 2 leaves; 28 cm. Dated 26 vend.re an 8.
    - Letters to citoyen Faure, 1798-1799 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      Physical Description: 15 leaves; 28 cm.
      Summary: Letters to Faure at the press of citoyen Dupont in Paris, from Brongniard, Lasteyrie, Harmand, and others.
    - Documents concerning the printing of assignats, 1792-1815 (Box 49, Folder 12)